Guide to the British manuscripts collection, 1560-1934
Department of Special Collections
British manuscripts collection,
1560-1934
Special Collections M0129
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Various sources
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Legal documents, letters and a manuscript history all pertaining to Great Britain or her colonies or written by or about citizens of same (The Bonnards later in California). 1660 - 1935.
To M415
One oversize folder of English legal documents on vellum dating from 1560 to 1799. -
CONTAINER LIST
- BLACKADAR, HENRY (Nova Scotia lawyer) - Archibald McQueen (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. 1827, July 1.Articles of agreement and Archibald McQueen and Archibald McQueen, Jr. Jr. bound or apprenticed as clerk to H. B.
  - 2. 1832, July 6.A. McQueen, Jr. certificate of service signed by H. Blackadar, McQueen's signed deposition and Examiner's certificate.
  - 3. 1832, July 24.Certificate of McQueen's admission to the bar.
- BONNARD PAPERS (Glasgow, Scotland) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. 1810, Oct. 17.A.L.S. John Wilson to Miss M. Murray.
  - 2. 1818, July 27 & Nov. 30.(Glasgow) Notes of loans to James Alexander Paul & Co. by Murray & Bonnard, sent to David Stow.
  - 3. 1819, June 5.Murray & Bonnard. Copy of a bill.
  - 4. 1828, Aug. 9.(London) Marg & Bonnard to Frances [Francis] Bonnard. Letter to a schoolboy.
  - 5. 1830, July 6.(London) Apprenticeship papers of Francis Alexander Bonnard to Robert Spottiswoode, stationer.
  - 6. 1875, May 9.(San Francisco) F. A. Bonnard to Nellie [Bonnard].
- [ BURKE, EDMUND] 1729 - 1797 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [ca. 1791]A.L. to [Sir Philip Francis] & typescript.
    MOVED TO MISC 019
- CECIL, [LORD] HUGH [RICHARD HEATHCOTE] 1869 - (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1912, June 29.T.L.S. to Mrs. Cobden-Sanderson. Re: women's suffrage & Franchise Bill.
    [UNK]
- FLAWITH, RICHARD & THOMAS MASON (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1756, Oct. 13.Indenture. Exchange deed of lands in Alno, Yorkshire, England. GIFT: Hutton Webster
- GREY, [ Charles] 1804 - 1870 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1856, Oct. 7.(Balmoral Castle). A.L.S. to John Gray. Thanks him by command of Prince Albert & [Queen Victoria] for copy of the Memorials of James Watt.
- JOYNES, EDWARD JOHN BLAND (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1. 1802, May 18.Indenture of apprenticeship to Adam Mew, framework knitter of Nottingham. Signature of John Davison, mayor & George Oldham, town clerk.
  - 2. 1809, Aug. 15.Certificate of office & signed oath as Burgess of Nottingham.
  - 3. 1814, July 25.Discharge from Derbyshire Militia. GIFT: Charles F. Reindollar, 1936.
- LANGLY, A. F. (Box 1, Folder 7(a))
  - 1891, Mar. 17(Wales). To [?] from Langly indicating he has sent copies of the M.I.'s in the old Broseley church.
- LICHFIELD, COUNTESS OF (Box 1, Folder 7b)
  - Commonplace Book containing poetic extracts dating [1818-1825]
- MAINWARING, H.G. (Box 1, Folder 7c)
  - Newspaper obituary, BRIGHTON COMPANY TIMES, n.d. June 22
  - Calling card, Mrs. MAINWARING
  - ANS: Mrs. MAINWARING to Mr. GORDON, n.d. Apr. 29
- PARKER, GEORGE (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1887, Feb. 28.A.L.S. to Reginald Horton. Re: Breeches Bible, London, Barker, 1603 with sketches or rubbings with notes from cover of Horton's copy.
- POOLE, REGINALD STUART 1832 - 1895 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1878, Jan. 26.L.S. to unknown.
- SHARP, ISAAC (Box 1, Folder 10a)
  - ALS, 1888to Ida, with transcript
- SMITH, ADAM - facsimile 1723 - 1790 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1776, June 3.To unknown (orig. at Huntington).
- STAMP, SIR JOSIAH CHARLES 1880 - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1935, Feb. 11.T.L.S. to [Ray Lyman] Wilbur.
- WRIGHT, J. M. F. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1830, Oct. 13.To Professor Wallace, A.L.S.